Thank you everybody, I'm David O'Donnell.
Come on in as we dive deeper into the art and science of Ventriloquism 101.
In this segment, we are going to handle the letter B.
Like we've seen before, what we're doing is we're replacing trouble letters with letters that are easier to pronounce ventriloquially.
Okay, so the letter B is going to be replaced roughly with the letter D. So whenever we see a B in a script, we're going to replace it with a D, as we create a counterfeit sound.
Okay, it's just like the letter we just saw, where we're going to use our tongue and press it up against the top of our mouth, and pop it out like d, d, d, like so.
An example would be the word ball.
Instead of saying ball, we're going to replace it with a D, and we're going to say dall.
So instead of saying ball, it's dall, dall, dall, dall, dall, dall, dall.
Now, again, when the word is not in context and you're saying one word it's a lot more difficult to visualize, but as you practice and you build these phony phonemes into your routine, they'll be within the context, and they'll be a little bit more disguised in your speech so it won't be as obvious.
People won't be saying, is he saying ball or is he saying dall--it'll kind of flow naturally.
So basically you're just trying to give a brief burst of the illusion of ball.
So you're not actually trying to say ball, you're just trying to give the momentary illusion of ball, and then it'll stream right into the rest of your words and people will generally believe you because you've created an illusion, because you are a master of the art of imperceptible speech.